

BACKEND ENGINEER · CHIEF TECHNOLOGY OFFICER

25 Emir Abdelkader Avenue, Akid Lotfi, Bir Eldjir 31000, Oran, Algeria

🛘 (+213) 551-081-911 | 🔀 salim@zidweb.com | 🌴 salimdj.me | 🔂 CaddyDz | 🤟 CaddyDz | 💆 Salim-djerbouh | 🛅 CaddyDz | 💆 🕞

"He who says he can and he who says he can't are both usually right"

Summary.

Current Chief Technology Officer and Lead Developer at start-up company Zidweb. 5+ years experience specializing in the backend development, infrastructure automation, and data structures and pattern architecture. Super nerd who loves Vim, Linux and OS X and enjoys to customize all of the development environment. Interested in devising a better problem-solving method for challenging tasks, and learning new technologies and tools if the need arises.

Skills_

DevOps Linux, Digital Ocean, Vagrant, Travis CI, GitHub Actions, CloudFlare, Stripe, Algolia, Pusher, Vonage

Back-end Laravel, NodeJS, ASP.NET Core, MySQL, Redis, REST API, Swagger

Front-end VueJS, VueX, Nuxt, WebPack, Babel, HTML5, CSS3, Vuetify Material, TWBS, jQuery **Programming** C#, PHP, Python, Perl, Java, Ruby, Objective-C, Swift, C/C++, BASH, ASM x86_64 AT&T, D

Languages English, French, Arabic

Work Experience_

Zidweb, LLC. Oran, Algeria

CO-FOUNDER, CTO AND LEAD DEVELOPER

Feb. 2020 - Present

- Provisioned an easily manageable hybrid infrastructure(Digital Ocean Droplets + On-premise) utilizing IaC(Infrastructure as Code) tools like Sentry and OpenVPN
- Manage all DevOps and third party services integration (CloudFlare, Forge, Algolia, Pusher, Vonage)
- Built fully automated CI/CD pipelines on Travis CI and GitHub Actions for containerized applications using Docker and Vagrant.
- Implemented, documented RESTful API server for directory listing application (Easy Help in Google Play).
- Wrote and deployed several small scale apps like shopping carts.
- Restructured a +40 million records database of automotive spare parts catalog and implemented a web interface for it
- Created a medical platform to manage requests for operations abroad as well as handle transportation and hotel booking
- Created Backend in Laravel + Frontend in NuxtJS for an ELO Boosting gaming service.

Didata LLC. Zürich, Switzerland

FULL STACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER

March. 2020 - April. 2020

- Wrote example testing data seeders for BioLab research application
- Implemented an ACL architecture for Backend API
- Wrote mutations mapping module for state management following the Flux pattern for the Frontend application
- Implemented several CRUD models

Upwork. Germany

FREELANCE BACKEND DEVELOPER

Feb. 2020

- Wrote and integrated a library for ActiveCampaign mailing lists and contact
- Upgraded framework and libraries versions and refactored code accordingly

EURL PAKIKI Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia

ACCOUNTING AND RESEARCH OPERATIONS

Nov. 2019 - Dec. 2019

- $\bullet \ \ \text{Implemented several data collection and visualization graphs for sales and expenses of the corporation}$
- Created an instant search iPad application implementing Algolia as well as Apple ARKit 4 for vendors in showrooms
- Installed an configured an RTMP server for live camera feed

A-Tech Solutions LLC. Algiers, Algeria

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

Jan. 2019 - March. 2019

Feb. 2018 - Sep. 2019

- Wrote an HRM Module in ASP.NET Core for an ERP Platform
- Ported an existing application to Linux environment
- Wrote a CRUD view module in AngularJS

SARL TPHST.

Algiers, Algeria

INTERNATIONAL RELATIONS CONSULTING AND IT SUPPORT

- Managed foreign partners (BSolar, AcoClara, Aquamarine and Leica) meetings, calls and emails
- Done market research for importing machinery from the EU
- Created an API client in C for fingerprint based office employees check-in device
- Configured cloud based backing and syncing services for documents across the administration
- Automated documents scanning by integrating a third party OCR service in Windows

JANUARY 19, 2021 DJERBOUH SALIM · RÉSUMÉ

Bitshopit Algiers, Algeria

CO-FOUNDER AND LEAD DEVELOPER

• FIFA 2018 video streaming site, implemented RTMP, Redis queues, ffmpeg encoding, VideoJS HLS and Google IMA VAST

· Database architecture, business logic and API integration of Binance cryptocurrency exchange platform

• Created a webfront site for a medical clinic and managed its SEO to top Google hits and Alexa rank

AlgoTech Orestor LLC. Algiers, Algeria Mar. 2017 - Dec. 2017 LEAD DEVELOPER AND SYSTEM ADMIN

• Created an automated online store shopping cart with themes and ordering system

• Implemented the deployment infrastructure on Linux Debian via bind9 and automated nginx configuration

MNI Martship Algiers, Algeria

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

· Wrote the RTL version of the shopping section on company's site

• Implemented responsive and re-sizable media for faster page loads

Galaxy EDU Boumerdas, Algeria FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER Aug. 2016, Mar. 2017

· Created a web based private school management system with online level testing system and evaluation

Wrote Microsoft Office Excel add-ons in VBA to integrated an HRM module

Honors & Awards

INTERNATIONAL

2016-2021 Top %5, Overall Stack Overflow members

2018-2021 Top #37, PHP ranking GitHub awards

DOMESTIC

2021 1st Place, Most Active GitHub contributor Algeria

Nov. 2017

May. 2017

Algiers, Algeria

Sep. 2016 - Oct. 2017

International Amsterdam,

Netherlands

Apr. 2018 - Dec. 2018

Jun. 2017, Aug. 2017

Presentation

GDG Conference Blida, Algeria

PRESENTER FOR < MACHINE LEARNING THEORY>

Introduced the theory of machine learning genetic algorithms with an analogy of evolutionary biology

• Introduced how machine learning algorithms work with an implementation of an SAT resolver in symbolic regression

CSC Club VCS event Blida, Algeria

SPEAKER < PRODUCTIVE GIT AND GITHUB WORKFLOWS>

A step by step guide & live demo of GitHub teams workflow, from forks to clones to issues and pull requests to merges and releases.

OpenMinds Linux install party

A LOOK INTO THE KERNEL INTERNALS> Apr. 2017

• A brief talk about the Linux kernel source tree and subsystems with a short introduction to OSDev

Education

Harvard University Remote

Oct. 2017 - Jan. 2018 HARVARD CS50

• Passed final tests creating a web server and reverse proxy in C.

USTHB University Algiers, Algeria

FIRST YEAR MATHS AND COMPUTER SCIENCE

• Dropped out due to outdated material and language barrier (French), switched to self education

Lounici Ali University Blida, Algeria

Sep. 2013 - Jan. 2016 FINAL YEAR ENGLISH LITERATURE

• Dropped out due to lack of interest, switched to computer science

JANUARY 19, 2021 DJERBOUH SALIM · RÉSUMÉ